Contact

San Diego, California 858-740-1389 (Mobile) tnoles@eplus.com

www.linkedin.com/in/thanielnoles (LinkedIn)

www.gtcsystems.com (Company)

Top Skills

Data Center

Citrix

VMware

Languages

English

Certifications

Citrix Virtualization Specialist Practicum

CompTIA Linux (Powered by LPI)

CCIA for Citrix XenApp

VMware Certified Professional 4 - Data Center Virtualization

Nutanix Platform Sales Rep (NPSR) Certification

Honors-Awards

2011 IT Executive of the Year Finalist

2012 Information Technology Executive Of The Year Awards

2012 Top Tech Exec Finalists

2013 IT Executive Of The Year Finalists

2014 America's Most Honored Profesionals

Thaniel Noles

Principal Architect at ePlus inc.

San Diego, California

Summary

15+ years of diverse technology and management experience.

Extensive experience in Designing, Deploying and Managing Enterprise deployments of VMware, Citrix, Microsoft, Cisco and supporting infrastructure technologies including SAN, backup, disaster recovery and multi-site data center operations.

Proven and recognized leadership, oversight, and direction to plan, build and manage leading technologies for a 500+ customer base encompassing a wide range of industries including Healthcare, Finance, Education and Biotech.

Lead strategic technological planning and implementation to achieve business goals by prioritizing technology initiatives and coordinating the evaluation, deployment, and management of existing and future technologies.

United States Navy Veteran - Active Security Clearance.

Subject Matter Expert Guest Speaker - for various conferences to share technology best practices and lessons learned.

November 2014 - Cloud Conference Hosted by AITP - Thaniel Noles is Chief Technical Officer of GTC Systems Inc. (www.gtcsystems.com) and the main Architect of The GTC Public Cloud (www.gtccloud.com). He is a Virtualization, Storage and Networking expert.

August 2013 - VDI Best Practices at Angelbeat IT conferences in southern California - Best practices to Plan, Build and Manage a VDI infrastructure, including those related to Server Hardware, Hypervisor, Storage, Network, Applications, Power Management,

Processor Hyper-threading, DNS, Recent Challenges, and how the GTC technical team overcame them.

Experience

ePlus inc.

Principal Architect February 2017 - Present

ePlus inc. (PLUS Nasdaq) provides world-class IT products and services through top level manufacturer certifications, and patented enterprise software and business processes. Specialties include Data Center & Cloud Automation, IT Security, Professional Services, Managed Services, Infrastructure & Networking, Collaboration & Unified Communications, and B2B Software.

ePlus is a top nationwide provider of Cisco, HP, Palo Alto, Splunk, Gigamon, VMware, CommVault, NetApp, EMC, Tegile, Pure, Tintri, VMware, Veeam, Citrix, Extrahop and many other world-class manufacturer solutions.

Can your existing partners help you in ALL of the areas listed below? If not, contact me to see how my team provides these world-class solutions to our local San Diego clients:

- DATA CENTER SOLUTIONS Converged Infrastructure Cloud + Virtualization Storage
- COLLABORATION Unified Communications Advanced Video, Audio & Web Conferencing
- SECURITY Assessments Security Services Software & Appliance Partner Solutions
- INFRASTRUCTURE Networking Wireless BYOD + VDI Partner Products Line Card
- SERVICES Staff Augmentation Project Management Managed Services
- Procurement
- SOFTWARE Procurement Supplier & Catalog Mgmt Asset & Maintenance Contract Mgmt
- FINANCIAL IT Equipment & Software Financing Swing Gear & Rentals Nationwide Rollouts

GTC Systems

Chief Technology Officer - Senior Systems Engineer June 2007 - February 2017 (9 years 9 months)

Page 2 of 4

Professional Services – Responsible for customer facing implementation services for a variety of Virtualization technologies including Microsoft, Citrix, Cisco and VMware. Direct technical resources and provide support in their operations as customer facing consultants. These resources are responsible for delivery of implementation of a variety of enterprise virtualization technologies. Provide presales consultation with the customer to identify the vision and purpose for the technology or service being deployed. Create scope of work and project plan documentation.

Cloud Services - Designed and implemented a multi-site robust infrastructure to provide customer hosting of applications, desktop services, and infrastructure as a service. Responsible for the day to day help desk, administration and data center operations for hosted customers.

Managed Services - Responsible for providing the People, Process and Technology to support on premise or hosted technology infrastructure. Created service level agreements and standard operating procedures for a team of service technicians and systems engineers to provide the day to day management of technology.

Technology Evaluation – Work with manufacturers and vendors to research, evaluate, and select the best of breed products that provide value to our customers. Current technology evaluation and adoption include Nutanix and Simplivity hyper-converged technologies, RES software to enable IT automation and User Personalization.

DataWorks, Inc Director of Information Technology June 2004 - June 2007 (3 years 1 month)

Created Software as a service (SaaS) offering for the NeXt retail management software. Created cost models, service level agreements and operational procedures for the hosted application delivery.

Planned and managed budget for the acquisition of data center collocation space, support personnel hardware and software resources to provide SaaS services in a multi-tenant hosted service offering.

Successfully implemented a PCI compliant architecture creating the opportunity for being awarded a hosting contract for a global hotel chain to

establish a site to site VPN between data centers gain access to the point of sales systems at each of the properties.

Provided services to software developers both local and abroad as well as escalation support for the customer service support desk.

ComputerLand Senior Systems Engineer February 1997 - July 1999 (2 years 6 months)

Designs and developed solutions to complex computer applications problems, system administration issues, and network concerns. Performed systems design integration and management functions.

Education

Coleman College
Computer Science Network and Application Support

University of Hawaii AA, Liberal Arts